Ted Key Papers
Ted Key Papers
1937-2008
Key, Ted.
46 linear ft.
Original artwork for over 4,500 magazine and snydicated cartoons (including Hazel); commercial artwork; correspondence; screenplays; scripts for the Hazel television show; writings; promotional material; proofs and memorabilia.
149103
Biographical History
Ted Key (1912-2008) was an American cartoonist and writer who is best known for creating the character "Hazel".
Ted Key was born on August 25, 1912 in Fresno, California as Theodore Keyser. His father, a Latvian immigrant, changed the family name (originally Katseff) to Key during World War I. After graduating from the University of California- Berkeley in 1933, where he was art editor of the student newspaper and associate editor of the college magazine, Key moved to New York City and worked as a freelance cartoonist and wrote for the J. Walter Thompson Advertising Agency. While in New York, Key joined the Cartoonists Guild of America in an effort to increase the amount of money received for his work. During World War II, Key served in a public relations capacity with the United States Army Signal Corps.
Key developed the Hazel character, a maid and related characters Mr. and Mrs. Baxter, cats: Two Ton and Mostly; and dogs: Smiley and Schnoozel. The idea was picked up by the Saturday Evening Post in 1943 and cartoons featuring her Hazel began appearing in the magazine. The Saturday Evening Post retained exclusive rights to the character while it was published in the magazine. Hazel replaced the panel Little Lulu and became a regular monthly feature until the Saturday Evening Post ceased publication in 1969. However, Hazel was picked up by the King Features Syndicate and they began publishing the cartoon six days a week. Key adapted the Hazel character for other mediums. Hazel was used in promotional material and Key wrote a movie and musical treatments. Hazel was also successfully adapted into a non-animated television series, starring Shirley Booth. The show, produced by Screen Gems, aired initially on NBC for four seasons starting in 1961. The show as brought to a conclusion on CBS in 1966.
Key also published gag cartoons in other magazines including Collier's and This Week. In addition to drawing cartoons, Key illustrated motivational materials published by Economics Press designed for children and businesses under the titles Positive Attitude and A Sales Bullet. Also a writer, Key authored the children's book Phyllis and wrote screenplays, several of which were produced as Walt Disney movies. These films, The Million Dollar Duck (1971), Gus (1976), The Cat from Outer Space (1978), all featured animals as leading characters. Key is also credited with also wrote the story for Digby, the Biggest Dog in the World (1973), which was produced in the United Kingdom. Key is also credited with creating the characters Peabody and Sherman.
The National Cartoonists Society named Hazel the Best Newspaper Panel cartoon in 1977. Key was also active with the Pi Lambda Phi Fraternity, Big Brothers/Big Sisters of America and was a speaker at the 1957 Canadian National Exposition.
For much of his career, Ted Key worked out of his home outside of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Key retired in 1993 and died on May 3, 2008.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Ted Key Papers are arranged in seven series. The majority of the material in the collection is related to Key's Hazel character which appeared as a: syndicated cartoon, magazine cartoon and television show. Also available is material related to Key's work in motion pictures and original artwork by other artists. The collection includes printed material, original artwork, writings, and correspondence.
Artwork (1942-1993) is the largest series containing original artwork for the Hazel panel cartoon as it appeared as a syndicated cartoon for King Features Syndicate (3,925 cartoons) and as a magazine cartoon in the Saturday Evening Post (over 300 cartoons). There are also non-Hazel gag cartoons that were published in magazines such as Collier's and This Week (over 600 cartoons). In the inventory portion of this finding aid, there are links to two PDFs of item-level lists of magazine cartoons created by Key. Please note, these lists have not been verified.
The magazine cartoons have been numbered by Key and are primarily from 1942 through the 1960s. These items measure approximately 11" x 15" and were drawn in ink on paperboard. Many originals, particularly of Hazel have paper overlays on which pigment was applied for spot color (typically yellow). Captions are written in pencil. On back are numbers assigned by Key, the date of publication and publication name. The collection includes some full color cartoons as well as several are multiple page spreads. The collection also includes artwork for Hazel as a syndicated panel cartoon from 1969-1993. Earlier years measure 11 ½" x 14 ½" and have captions written in pencil. Work from the 1980s and 1990s measures 7 ½" x 9" and captions have been typed and pasted on. The Hazel syndicated cartoon was drawn in ink.
Also included in this series is original color artwork for Diz and Liz which appeared in Jack and Jill magazine; miscellaneous original artwork by Key; and cartoons by other artists including several pieces for Life magazine. In addition to magazine and syndicated cartoons, there is rough artwork for the Positive Attitude posters and A Sales Bullet illustrations Key produced. These posters feature positive aphorisms about being a good person and a good employee, such as "The right way…is the best way" and "Doing your share helps get the job done!". These roughs were done in watercolor on paper and are numbered and dated. Also included are rough ideas that were rejected.
Correspondence (1943-2002) contains incoming letters from fellow cartoonists Syd Hoff, Lynn Johnston (as well as her niece) and Ed Nofziger as well as a small sampling of fan mail. Key also corresponded with Adlai Stevenson, Bess Truman, Hazel television star, Shirley Booth and children's author Betty MacDonald.
The Personal series (1957-1986) consists of mementos, including a placard for the NBC spelling bee and a handkerchief embroidered with the name Hazel; a photograph of Key; and awards including a letter from Syracuse University.
Promotional material (1940s-2004) includes a variety of printed material using the Hazel character as well as publicity for movies written by Key including posters and press kits.
Proofs (1954-2008) is comprised almost entirely of proof sheets the Hazel syndicated panel cartoon. Each week appears on a single sheet. There are two sets of proofs for most years; some sets are not complete. There are a few also miscellaneous proofs for magazine cartoons and a Hazel book.
Writings (1960-1998) consist of proposals, screenplays, treatments and scripts for Hazel related productions as well as Key's screenplays for the motion pictures Cat From Outer Space, Digby the Biggest Dog in the World, Gus and Million Dollar Duck. The series includes material for ideas that were never produced including a memoir. The Hazel television scripts are not written by Key and for several other titles, Key worked with collaborators who have been named in this inventory where available. The series also contains handwritten gags for Hazel. Often these sheets are dated at the top with a week's date range. Some gags have been crossed out as "drawn" and some contain very rough sketches drawn in ballpoint pen.
Miscellaneous (1942-1992) includes clippings, book dummies, published material, a typed translation taken from a Norwegian Hazel book and a cassette tape recording of a Toonerviews interview with Ted Key, Chon Day, Fred Lasswell, Hank Ketcham and Chance Brown.
Arrangement of the Collection
Magazine cartoons have been arranged by date and separated into Hazel and non-Hazel sections within each year. Syndicated cartoons are arranged in chronological order. Correspondence is arranged in alphabetical order by sender.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Published works related to Hazel and Key's other work are located in Rare Books. Please use the SUMMIT catalog to locate these materials.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Radio, television, film; Key, Ted.; King Features Syndicate.; Hazel (cartoon); Hazel (Television series); Saturday evening post.; Million dollar duck (motion picture); Gus (motion picture); The cat from outer space.; Digby the biggest dog in the world.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Animals in motion pictures.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Comic books, strips, etc.; Motion picture plays.; Screenwriters -- United States.; Women household employees -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Clippings (information artifacts); Promotional materials.; Proofs (printed matter); Correspondence.; Memorabilia.; Scripts (documents); Screenplays.; Cartoonists.; Screenwriters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ted Key, 1963-1964, 1966-1969, 1971-1974, 1978, 1990, 2000.
Gift of Peter Key, 2009-2010.
Illustration, gift of Martin McDermott, 2021
Inventory
- Artwork
  - Commercial art, roughs
    - Energy posters, undated (Box 12)
      #5
    - Positive Attitude (P.A.), 1980-1991 (Box 12)
      #397-493, 500-684 with some gaps
    - Sales Bullet, 1980s (Box 13)
      #631, 662-686, 711-896 with some gaps
    - Rejects, circa 1980s (Box 14)
    - Unidentified, circa 1980s; likely for Positive Attitude and/or Sales Bullet (Box 14)
  - Hazel syndicated cartoon, 3,925 items; Click here for a detailed inventory.
    - 1969 Jan, 1969 Jun, 1969 Aug-Nov (Oversize 1)
    - 1969 Dec (Oversize 2)
    - 1970 Jan-Aug (Box 1)
    - 1970 Sep-Dec (Oversize 2)
    - 1971 Jan (Oversize 3)
    - 1971 Feb-Sep (Box 2)
    - 1971 Oct-1972 Feb (Oversize 3)
    - 1972 Mar-Dec (Oversize 4)
    - 1973 Jan-Dec (Oversize 5)
    - 1974 Jan-1975 May (Oversize 6)
    - 1975 Jun-Dec, 1976 Feb, 1976 May, 1977 Oct, also includes 3 undated unfinished cartoons/sketches (Oversize 7)
    - 25 Jan 1980, 1981 Oct-Dec, 1982 Feb-Mar, 1982 Oct, 1984 Apr-Dec, 1985 Apr-1986 Feb, 1986 Apr, 1986 Oct, 5 Dec 1987, 1988 Feb-Mar, 1988 May-Jul, 1988 Sep-Oct, 1989 Jan-Apr, 1989 Jun-Dec (Box 3)
    - 1990 Jan-Nov (Box 4)
    - 1990 Dec-1991 May (Box 5)
    - 1991 Jun-Dec (Box 6)
    - 1992 Jan-Jul (Box 7)
    - 1992 Aug-1993 Feb (Box 8)
    - 1993 Mar-Jun (Box 9)
  - Magazine cartoons, Click here to view a detailed inventory of Hazel cartoons and their numbers, captions and publication date. Click here to view a detailed inventory of non-Hazel magazine cartoons and their numbers, captions and publication date. Please note these inventories were provided by Key and have not been verified for accuracy and completeness.
    - 1942 non- Hazel (Oversize 8)
      92, 324, 335
    - 1943 non-Hazel (Oversize 8)
      69, 74, 97, 102, 140, 161, 191-192, 260, 282, 613, 742, 753
    - 1944 Hazel (Oversize 8)
      108
    - 1944 non-Hazel (Oversize 8)
      77, 202, 332, 469
    - 1945 Hazel (Oversize 8)
      161, 311, 338
    - 1945 non-Hazel (Oversize 8)
      unnumbered, 89, 144, 353, 439, 443, 490
    - 1946 Hazel (Oversize 8)
      21, 24, 57, 297, 299, 312, 324
    - 1946 Hazel (Oversize 9)
      293, 295, 473, 476, 506, 507, 513
    - 1946 non-Hazel (Oversize 8)
      104, 121, 135, 139, 155
    - 1946 non-Hazel (Oversize 9)
      158, 163, 172, 198, 205, 275, 287, 294, 298, 325, 352, 470, 472, 489, 491, 493, 494, 506, 507, 559, 564, 567, 595
    - 1946 non-Hazel (Oversize 10)
      602, 603, 604, 617, 618, 648, 737, 738, 740, 741
    - 1947 Hazel (Oversize 10)
      13, 14, 16, 17, 20, 58, 298, 484, 512
    - 1947 non-Hazel (Oversize 10)
      5, 7, 8, 22, 29, 39. 40, 43, 51, 61, 68
    - 1947 non-Hazel (Oversize 11)
      103, 125, 127, 129, 141, 142, 143, 145, 153, 156, 157, 159, 169, 170, 171, 195, 217, 243, 259, 289, 401, 402, 441, 444, 465, 471, 488, 492
    - 1947 non-Hazel (Oversize 12)
      504, 508, 525, 556, 560, 578, 579, 605-612, 614, 619, 638, 639, 743-745, 754, 756, 757, 759, 763, 764, 765, 766
    - 1948 Hazel (Oversize 13)
      9-12, 15, 18-19, 53-54, 59, 104-105, 139, 143-144, 149, 289-291, 294, 296, 302, 314, 315, 486, 516
    - 1948non-Hazel (Oversize 14)
      4, 32, 54, 62, 76, 83, 96, 122, 126, 137, 146, 152, 165, 175, 177, 186, 193, 261-263, 293, 295, 297, 453, 468, 481, 482, 486
    - 1948 non-Hazel (Oversize 15)
      487, 503, 505, 511, 561, 565, 571, 622-627, 637, 728-736, 746, 755, 760, 762
    - 1949 Hazel (Oversize 16)
      22, 23, 27, 43, 102, 103, 106, 109, 146, 151-153, 158, 164-166, 173, 194, 303, 313, 316, 340-342, 504
    - 1949 non-Hazel (Oversize 17)
      6, 9, 17, 21, 30, 56, 70, 73, 75, 91, 93, 95, 118, 124, 132, 150, 154, 160, 164, 173, 178, 187, 188, 194, 206, 209, 210
    - 1949 non-Hazel (Oversize 18)
      245, 258, 267, 288, 299, 336, 346, 403, 404, 458, 477, 483, 495, 498, 500, 502, 524, 562, 580, 583, 615, 616, 634-636, 640-643
    - 1949 non-Hazel (Oversize 19)
      644-647, 747-748, 761
    - 1950 Hazel (Oversize 19)
      25, 26, 49, 55, 56, 83, 98, 130, 131, 141, 142, 154-156, 159, 193, 287
    - 1950 Hazel (Oversize 20)
      288, 292, 301, 318, 343, 452
    - 1950 non-Hazel (Oversize 20)
      3, 26, 46, 67, 71, 72, 79, 90, 94, 138, 162, 189, 211, 212, 225-227, 234, 246, 273, 296
    - 1950 non-Hazel (Oversize 21)
      337, 371, 440, 442, 456, 475, 478, 496, 558, 739, 749
    - 1951 Hazel (Oversize 21)
      60, 107, 129, 132, 140, 147, 150, 168-171, 195, 203, 317, 319-320, 344, 345
    - 1951 non-Hazel (Oversize 22)
      19, 24, 27, 45, 47, 63, 66, 80, 98, 100, 115, 117, 119, 128, 133, 176, 190, 197, 200, 201, 207, 208, 214
    - 1951 non-Hazel (Oversize 23)
      216, 222, 251, 254, 255, 272, 436-438, 450, 455, 464, 474, 476, 484, 499, 515, 517, 521
    - 1951 non-Hazel (Oversize 24)
      532-549, 563, 566, 573, 581, 628-633
    - 1952 Hazel (Oversize 25)
      50, 137, 145, 162, 172, 186, 209, 212, 216, 218, 232, 233, 235, 242, 245, 250, 252, 257, 259, 260, 300, 501, 505
    - 1952 non-Hazel (Oversize 26)
      35, 36, 42, 53, 59, 99, 106, 130, 149, 151, 168, 182, 183, 199, 215, 218, 223, 228, 249, 252, 264, 265, 270, 271, 279
    - 1952 non-Hazel (Oversize 27)
      281, 291, 292, 326, 327, 338, 341, 348, 351, 357, 360, 368, 369, 446, 451, 467, 473, 479, 485, 497,501, 514, 516, 518, 569, 596
    - 1953 Hazel (Oversize 28)
      163, 167, 180, 182-185, 188, 190-192, 198, 204-207, 210, 211, 213, 215
    - 1953 Hazel (Oversize 29)
      221, 223, 225, 227, 228, 230, 236, 239, 243, 244, 253, 257, 470
    - 1953 non-Hazel (Oversize 29)
      1, 11, 12, 37, 38, 41, 55, 57, 78, 101, 105
    - 1953 non-Hazel (Oversize 30)
      120, 123, 147, 148, 167, 174, 181, 219-221, 238, 242, 248, 266, 268, 276-278, 301-310
    - 1953 non-Hazel (Oversize 31)
      329, 340, 347, 359, 361, 432, 434, 448, 459, 480, 512, 513, 520, 526, 529, 574-576, 599
    - 1955 non-Hazel (Box 17)
      662-672 Saturday Evening Post spread "The Expert"
    - 1954 Hazel (Oversize 32)
      84, 134, 138, 157, 160, 174, 178, 181, 189, 196, 197, 199-202, 208, 214, 217, 219, 222, 224, 226, 229, 231
    - 1954 Hazel (Oversize 33)
      232, 237, 238, 240, 241, 247-249, 254-256, 258, 321, 327, 331
    - 1954 non-Hazel (Oversize 33)
      13, 14, 23, 25, 28, 33, 34, 51, 64
    - 1954 non-Hazel (Oversize 34)
      65, 108, 110-112, 116, 224, 229A, 229B, 235, 240, 241, 256, 257, 269, 274, 285, 328, 330, 331, 355, 370, 399, 400
    - 1954 non-Hazel (Oversize 35)
      433, 452, 460, 510, 519, 527, 528, 550-555, 584-594, 597, 598
    - 1954 non-Hazel (Box 35)
      768-778 - all for Colliers
    - 1955 Hazel (Oversize 36)
      133, 136, 175, 176, 179, 187, 220, 234, 246, 310, 322, 328, 370
    - 1955 non-Hazel (Oversize 36)
      10, 20, 44, 49, 88, 107, 109, 113, 114, 134, 230, 237, 247, 280, 284
    - 1955 non-Hazel (Oversize 37)
      290, 300, 311-323, 339, 356, 365, 372, 392-398
    - 1955 non-Hazel (Oversize 38)
      435, 449, 509, 577, 582, 601
    - 1955 non-Hazel (Box 35)
      655-661 - all for Colliers
    - 1955 non-Hazel (Box 17)
      701-705 This Week spread "The Extroverts"
    - 1956 Hazel (Oversize 38)
      2, 5, 6, 16, 46, 93-95, 325, 329, 330, 332-337, 339, 347, 348
    - 1956 Hazel (Oversize 39)
      349, 352, 353, 355, 356, 359-364, 368, 369
    - 1956 non-Hazel (Oversize 39)
      15, 48, 52, 81, 82, 131
    - 1956 non-Hazel (Oversize 40)
      131, 136, 166, 180, 184, 185, 196, 253, 333, 350, 358, 364, 386-391, 405, 406, 408, 411-414, 457
    - 1956 non-Hazel (Oversize 41)
      461, 466, 530, 600, 781
    - 1956 non-Hazel (Box 35)
      649-654 - all for Colliers
    - 1955 non-Hazel (Box 17)
      407, 409-410, 415 Saturday Evening Post spread "Theirs and Ours"
    - 1957 Hazel (Oversize 41)
      1, 44, 97, 101, 128, 326, 346, 350, 351, 354, 357, 358, 365-367, 455, 456, 463, 481, 500
    - 1957 non-Hazel (Oversize 42)
      50, 60, 86, 87, 179, 250, 334, 342, 349, 354, 362, 366, 367, 373-385
    - 1957 non-Hazel (Oversize 43)
      416-422, 462, 568, 572, 620
    - 1958 Hazel (Oversize 43)
      4, 7, 8, 18, 30, 31, 33, 42, 45, 48, 96, 113, 124-127, 135
    - 1958 Hazel (Oversize 44)
      276, 277, 285, 286, 458, 459, 477, 482, 510, 515, 517
    - 1958 non-Hazel (Oversize 44)
      85, 239, 343, 363, 423-431, 463, 508, 522, 557, 570, 717, 718
    - 1958 non-Hazel (Oversize 45)
      719-727
    - 1959 Hazel (Oversize 45)
      64, 68, 71, 76-77, 82, 85-86, 89-90, 100, 110-111, 114-115, 119, 121-123
    - 1959 Hazel (Oversize 52)
      148, 263, 265, 268-272, 278, 280-282, 284, 304-306, 308-309, 453, 457, 460, 478, 490, 498-499, 502, 509
    - 1959 non-Hazel (Oversize 47)
      84, 213, 233, 344, 523, 531, 706-716
    - 1959 non-Hazel (Box 35)
      686-692 - all for Saturday Evening Post
    - 1960 Hazel (Oversize 47)
      3, 28, 32, 34-38, 40
    - 1960 Hazel (Oversize 48)
      41, 47, 65-67, 69-70, 74-75, 78, 80, 92, 99, 112, 116-118, 120, 261-262, 264, 266-267, 273-275, 279, 283, 307, 449
    - 1960 non-Hazel (Oversize 49)
      345
    - 1960 non-Hazel (Box 35)
      674-685 - all for Saturday Evening Post
    - 1961 Hazel (Oversize 49)
      29, 52, 62-63, 72-73, 79, 81, 87-88, 91, 433, 439, 450-451, 454, 475, 483
    - 1962 Hazel (Oversize 49)
      39, 448, 472, 485, 489, 496
    - 1963 Hazel (Oversize 50)
      177 (for the Saturday Evening Post but unpublished), 412, 418-419, 425, 427, 430, 432, 436, 442-443, 487-488, 495, 497, 503, 511
    - 1964 Hazel (Oversize 50)
      406-411, 415-417, 426, 428, 434, 437-438, 462, 491-492, 494
    - 1965 Hazel (Oversize 51)
      446, 493
    - 1966 Hazel (Oversize 51)
      413, 440, 444, 474
    - 1967 Hazel (Oversize 51)
      414, 421, 429, 435, 445, 464, 466, 469, 471, 479-480
    - 1968 Hazel (Oversize 51)
      423-424, 431, 441, 447, 465, 467-468
    - Undated Hazel (Oversize 51)
      2, 61, 2 items without numbers
    - 1970s-1980s Hazel, some list months of publication, many are undated (Oversize 55)
    - "Diz and Liz" for Jack and Jill, 1961-1966 (Oversize 46)
    - "Diz and Liz" for Jack and Jill, 1966-1968 (Box 16)
    - "Diz and Liz" for Jack and Jill, 1968 Apr-Dec (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Works by Key (Oversize 53)
      "Cheese It, The Carps!!", undated
      Clippings of Judge spread, 1937
      Clippings from New York World Telegram, 1937
      [Drawing of dancer], undated
      Hazel color crayon drawing, undated
      Hazel color drawing inscribed to Anne Key, 1971
      Hazel watercolor drawing inscribed to Anne Key, 1972
      Magazine cartoon, undated
      "Watch Out Everybody- the plate’s hot" (Hazel) Collier's, undated
      "You Must Excuse my Husband" 1939
      Untitled New Yorker cartoon, 1938
    - Works by Key (Oversize 54)
      [Hazel at sewing machine], undated
      Here’s Hazel book cover art, circa 1940s
      "Stare Him in the Eye…", 1937
      "Will You Do Us a Favor Before you Come Down", 1938
      Untitled, multiple panel spread, undated
    - Works by others (Oversize 53)
      Allen, Colin (inscribed to Ted and Anne Key)
      Artzybasheff, Boris Life magazine, undated
      Barker? Barber? Barbor?, P.
      Barlow, Perry, 2 items, undated
      Brustlein, Daniel "Alain", - 2 items, one depicting Hitler
      Gentry, Thurston, 2 items, undated
      Halton, Ned, 1938
      Halton, Ned, clipping, undated
      Unidentified, print
    - Works by others (Oversize 54)
      Barlow, Perry- Life magazine, undated
      Bundy, Gilbert- color, undated
      Decker, Richard- Life magazine, undated
      Frueh, Alfred Joseph- Life magazine, 2 items, undated
      McKay, Dorothy- Life magazine, undated
      Parker, Al- "The Gift Horse," undated
      Starrat, Kemp- Life magazine, undated
      Unidentified- [Orchard Street], undated
- Correspondence
  - A, C, G, H, P, 1943; 1946-1947,; 1952,; 1954 (Box 15)
  - Allen, Colin, 1995-1996 (Box 15)
  - Baldwin, Faith, undated (Box 15)
  - Berenstain, Michael, 1996 (Box 15)
  - Booth, Shirley, 1954 (Box 15)
  - Douglas, Kirk, 1991; regarding the Robert Meltzer Award (Box 15)
  - Fan mail, 1946; 1948,; 1964-1967,; 1971-1974,; undated; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Fan mail- children, 1961; 1963-1966,; 1973 (Box 15)
  - Hoff, Syd, 1995-1996 (Box 15)
  - Johnston, Lynn, 1988; 1990,; 1998-2002; 2 folders; includes copies of drawings (Box 15)
  - Kaltenborn, H. V., 1943 (Box 15)
  - MacDonald, Betty, 1947; undated (Box 15)
  - McDermott, Martin, circa 1970; signed and inscribed original illustration of Digby the Dog plus a sticker (Box 15)
    Gift of Martin McDermott, 2021
  - Nofziger, Ed, 1994-1996 (Box 15)
  - Rosenberg, Marvin, 1996 (Box 15)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, 1952 (Box 15)
  - Tabor, Gladys, 1956 (Box 15)
  - Truman, Bess, 1951-1952 (Box 15)
  - Unidentified, undated; note commenting on an ad for a "Hazel type General Housekeeper" (Box 15)
- Personal
  - Awards
    - American Lung Association plaque and letter, 1977 (Box 37)
    - Big Brothers/Big Sisters plaque, 1986 (Box 36)
    - Canadian National Exposition, 1957; 2 pieces (Box 36)
    - Certificates and correspondence, 1994; undated (Box 37)
    - National Cartoonists Society nomination certificates, 1961; 1971-1972,; 1974-1976 (Box 37)
    - Pi Lambda Phi Fraternity plaque, 1994 (Box 36)
    - Syracuse University, 1969 (Box 37)
    - Veteran's Administration, 1973 (Box 37)
  - Mementos
    - Spelling bee card, Hazel embroidered handkerchief, Hazel drawing, undated (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous
    - History of Plant Engineering Agency Army Communications Service, circa 1940s; original copy has been cataloged and transferred to Rare Books (Box 38)
    - Letter regarding health, undated (Box 37)
    - Photograph, undated (Box 37)
- Promotional material
  - Book publicity, 1940s; 1958; 2 items (Oversize 56)
  - Calendars, 1951; 1977-1978,; 1985 (Box 37)
    Big Brothers/Big Sisters of America
    "Cheerful Yearfull"
    "Just Waxed" (Johnson Wax)
  - Movie publicity
    - Cat from Outer Space movie poster, 1978 (Map-case 1, Drawer 107)
    - Digby the Biggest Dog in the World plastic bag, 1974 (Oversize 56)
    - Digby the Biggest Dog in the World press kit, 1974 (Box 34)
    - Digby the Biggest Dog in the World stickers, 1974 (Box 34)
    - Gus paper grocery bag, 1976; from Ralph's grocery store (Oversize 56)
    - Gus press materials, 1976 (Box 34)
    - Gus still photographs, circa 1976; 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Million Dollar Duck movie poster, 1971 (Map-case 1, Drawer 107)
    - Million Dollar Duck press kit, 1971 (Box 15)
    - Million Dollar Duck still photographs, 1971 (Box 15)